Skills HTML | CSS | SASS| JavaScript | React.js | Git | Bootstrap | JQuery | UX / UI | Adobe Creative Suite | Figma Cary, North Carolina, US 000-000-0000 yburdakova@hotmail.com yana-burdakova yburdakova yburdakova

Summary

Fast learner, adaptable and top motivated front-end developer with 2 years experience in designing and developing interactive web applications using HTML, CSS and JavaScript. Knowledge of Adobe Creative Suite and GitHub. Ability to work with UX / UI using Figma. Even though my experience in the frontend was obtained on freelance, I have an excellent background of interaction with the team, including in a distributed remote format and leading teamwork. Passionate about website responsiveness and accessibility.

Experience

Self-Employed Front-end Developer

Yana Burdakova, Front-end Developer

July 2020 - Present

- Design and development of web pages and landing pages with adaptive design based on the study of the customer's business processes using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React.js.
- Stay up to date with new technologies and completed 7 courses in front-end development and UI/UX design.
- Independently worked with clients to gather requirements, design, and implement solutions, delivering projects on time 100% and an average budget savings of 15%.
- Built and maintained strong relationships with clients, resulting in a 40% increase in repeat business and a 20% increase in positive word-of-mouth referrals.

Founder/Kinderlogia August 2017 - July 2020

- Successfully completed the design and development of the project from concept to completion.
- The concept of a profitable business model was developed, and detailed terms of reference were drawn up, which made it possible to attract 100% of the investments planned for the development of a prototype.
- Created and motivated a high-performing team of 8 professionals, providing mentoring and training for professional growth, resulting in a 50% increase in team performance.
- Launched a successful startup prototype with 1,500 active users organized into focus groups with a 30% conversion rate.
- Addressed operational issues proactively, resulting in a 23% increase in efficiency and cost savings.

Sr Learning Experience Designer / Russian Electronic School

July 2014 - July 2017

- Successfully managed projects resulting in 3 million daily users and 2 million daily unique views.
- Specialized in designing student learning experiences with a proven track record of delivering reliable student outcomes, resulting in a 20% increase in academic course performance.
- Expert in UX and UI design, contributing to the creation of concepts, layouts, and prototypes that improved user engagement by 15%.
- Implemented innovative solutions that positively impacted student satisfaction, resulting in a 25% increase in overall student satisfaction ratings.

Director / Pedagogical College

September 2003 - June 2014

- Grew from a teacher of the basics of computer science to a director.
- Fully automated methodological processes for the first time among educational institutions in the state and the transition to 100% paperless technology.
- Set ambitious school goals and provide teachers and students with appropriate, focused learning and professional development.

Education _____

- Bachelor of Computer Science, major in Applied Informatics, Kemerovo State University of Culture and Arts, Russia
- MS Social pedagogy, Kemerovo State University, Russia
- MS Educational management, Regional Institute of Professional Education Development, Kemerovo, Russia

Other

- Work authorized green card holder/ NC Driver license
- References available upon request